We have breaking news and a ruling that could decimate the landmark Voting Rights Act.
A panel of federal appeals court judges has ruled that only the federal government,
not citizens, not groups, can sue under a key part of the Voting Rights Act,
which effectively guts that legislation in seven states.
Joyce Vance is back with us.
That word decimate comes from UCLA election law expert,
who is Jane Tim, who wrote this story for us.
Talk to.
Is it that serious?
It is extremely serious.
But the first thing we should say, Chris,
is that this will now be appealed to the Supreme Court of the United States.
Although this is the law in the Eighth Circuit, the impact is in the future.
Because what this in essence does is it says that during a Republican administration in the future,
where the Justice Department might not be inclined to bring challenges under Section 2,
no one else could do it.
So that would mean that the cases that we've seen since the 2020 census
that have challenged racially motivated gerrymanders,
those types of lawsuits would cease to exist since they could only be brought by DOJ
and not by the private parties who routinely bring them,
unless the Supreme Court acts to reverse this decision.
So I'm going to start with you on the first slide,
so I should answer the question thing,
I wish I don't know what I want to be hearing,
but it does not affect the legitimacy of the curriculum.
To do that, depending on anything else,
I would also accept it as a change in mind that I can change over the course of the history.
I'll tell you what you said here on the full time.
So let's see what happens.
So let's say an April,
and this upon a personal piece of research is created by citrus journalists,
and we'll try to help a product 죄송 behind another episode Сергange.